Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Kathryn and we're going to the gym today, right Marco?
我是Kathryn，我们今天要去健身房，对吧，Marco？
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to go to the gym and we're going to try to lose weight or to get in shape.
今天我们要去健身房，尝试减肥或者塑形。
So before we start out though, there is a phrasal verb that we should take a look at.
不过在我们开始之前，有一个短语动词需要先看一下。
So today in Vocabulary Preview, we're looking at this phrase, to work out or working out.
所以在今天的词汇预览中，我们要看这个短语：to work out 或 working out。
That's right.
没错。
So when we go to the gym, this is what we do.
所以当我们去健身房时，这就是我们要做的事情。
We go there to work out, to exercise or to tone up.
我们去那里锻炼、运动或者塑形。
This is just a way of saying that I'm going to go somewhere like a gym to exercise myself.
这只是说我要去健身房之类的地方锻炼身体的一种方式。
That's right.
没错。
So with that in mind, we're going to go to the gym, we're going to work out and we're
所以带着这个想法，我们要去健身房，我们要锻炼，而且我们
going to learn a lot of words today about what exactly goes on in the gym.
今天会学到很多关于健身房具体活动的词汇。
Do you want to go catch a movie tonight?
今晚想去看电影吗？
I can't.
不行。
I have to go to the gym.
我得去健身房。
Come on.
别这样嘛。
You can go tomorrow.
你可以明天去。
Just skip it today.
今天就跳过吧。
It's not as if you're going to get in trouble.
又不是说你会惹上麻烦。
Actually, I will.
其实，我会的。
I'm working out with a personal trainer that gets on my case if I don't go.
我正在跟一个私人教练锻炼，如果我不去，他就会催我。
I like it because it makes me feel more obligated to go and get healthy.
我喜欢这样，因为它让我更有义务去锻炼，变得更健康。
That's cool.
那挺酷的。
Does your personal trainer basically teach you how to work out?
你的私人教练基本上是教你如何锻炼吗？
Yeah.
是的。
He makes a workout plan depending on the areas I want to work on or the muscles I want to
他会根据我想锻炼的部位或想练的肌肉制定一个锻炼计划，
build.
比如，为了让我腹肌、胸肌和二头肌的线条更好，他让我用自由重量训练。
Like for example, in order to get better muscle tone in my abs, pecs and biceps, he makes
然后对于我的股四头肌、小腿和腘绳肌，我会做抬腿或深蹲。
me work out with free weights.
听起来你确实在塑形了。
Then for my quads, calves and hamstrings, I do leg lifts or squats.
好的。
Sounds like you're really getting into shape.
那么，现在我们回来了。
All right.
让我们来看看“语言要点”部分。
So, now we're back.
“语言要点”。
Let's take a look at Language Takeaway.
好的。
Language Takeaway.
首先，在今天的对话中，我们听到了很多关于一个叫私人教练的人。
All right.
私人教练。
First of all, in today's dialogue, we heard a lot about this person called a personal
首先，在今天的对话中，我们听到了很多关于一个叫私人教练的人。
trainer.
私人教练。
What does a personal trainer do, Marco?
私人教练是做什么的，马可？
So basically, you have a person that is your coach, the person that guides you and teaches
基本上，就是有一个人当你的教练，指导你、教你
you how to work out or what you should do.
如何锻炼或者该做什么。
All right.
好的。
So, personal means it's just for me.
所以，“私人”意味着只为我服务。
This person is only helping me.
这个人只帮助我一个人。
A trainer is someone who, like you say, gives me guidance.
教练就是像你说的那样，给我指导的人。
So personal trainer is someone who will work with me every day or maybe one time a week
所以私人教练就是每天或每周一次和我一起工作的人，
to really get the most out of my workout.
让我的锻炼效果最大化。
That's right.
没错。
So that is a personal trainer.
这就是私人教练。
And as we said, he's going to help us to build muscle.
就像我们说的，他会帮助我们增肌。
We want to build muscle when we go to the gym.
我们去健身房就是想增肌。
All right.
好的。
So, this is an interesting one because the verb is not to grow or to make.
这个说法挺有意思，因为动词不是“生长”或“制造”。
The verb is to build.
动词是“建造”。
So, I have muscles, but I want my muscles to get bigger.
所以，我有肌肉，但我想让肌肉变大。
So I go to build muscles at the gym.
所以我去健身房增肌。
You might even hear this phrase, a bodybuilder.
你甚至可能听过这个词：健美运动员。
So this idea that you make them.
就是这种“制造”肌肉的概念。
Yeah, exactly.
对，没错。
So you don't get muscle.
所以你不会得到肌肉。
You don't create muscle.
你不会创造肌肉。
You build muscle.
你是锻炼肌肉。
And alongside with muscles, not only do you get them big, but you also get muscle tone.
而且除了让肌肉变大，你还能获得肌肉线条。
All right.
好的。
So muscle tone basically means definition.
所以肌肉线条基本上就是指轮廓清晰。
So maybe before you start to work out, your body is very soft.
也许在你开始锻炼之前，你的身体很软。
You can't see the muscles.
你看不到肌肉。
Well, when you start to see those muscles, you see the lines in your body.
嗯，当你开始看到那些肌肉时，你会看到身体上的线条。
Your skin gets tighter, not so soft.
你的皮肤变得更紧致，不那么软了。
That's called muscle tone.
这就叫肌肉线条。
That's right.
没错。
So then you can see the muscles.
所以那时你就能看到肌肉了。
That's muscle tone.
那就是肌肉线条。
And now the muscles that we most commonly go to the gym to work out, we're going to
现在，我们最常去健身房锻炼的肌肉，我们快速
name really quickly and we're going to see where they are.
说一下它们的名字，看看它们在哪里。
So the first one that we mentioned were abs.
第一个我们提到的是腹肌。
Okay.
好的。
This is an important one, especially if you want to go to the beach.
这个很重要，尤其是如果你想去海滩的话。
The abs are located on your stomach.
腹肌位于你的腹部。
So you see those kind of rectangles, those squares on your stomach.
所以你会看到腹部那些像矩形、方块一样的东西。
Those are the abs.
那些就是腹肌。
That's right.
没错。
And now for guys also, we want to work out our pecs or our pectoral muscles.
对于男性来说，我们也想锻炼胸肌或胸大肌。
So those are on your chest, below your neck, but above your stomach.
所以这些位于你的胸部，脖子下方，但腹部上方。
That's right.
没错。
And another important one on your arm, we have our biceps.
另一个重要的部位在手臂上，我们有肱二头肌。
All right.
好的。
Men usually like to show these off, or at least boys do.
男性通常喜欢炫耀这些，至少男孩们是这样。
These are on your arms.
这些在你的手臂上。
So you know when you make that L shape with your arm and you squeeze like Popeye?
你知道当你把手臂弯成L形，像大力水手那样用力时吗？
Those are your biceps.
那些就是你的肱二头肌。
Exactly.
完全正确。
And now, obviously going down towards our legs now, we have our quad muscles, our quads.
现在，显然往下到我们的腿部，我们有股四头肌。
All right.
好的。
So those are on the top part of your legs, right Marco?
所以这些位于你腿部的上半部分，对吧，Marco？
In front.
在前面。
So like on the top of your thigh.
就像在你大腿顶部的位置。
Exactly.
没错。
And now right behind the back part of your leg, you have your hamstrings.
现在，在你腿的后部，就是你的腘绳肌。
Hamstring.
腘绳肌。
Now you hear about this one a lot because people injure their hamstrings pretty easily
你经常听到这个词，因为人们在踢足球或跑步时很容易拉伤腘绳肌。
in football or in running.
在踢足球或跑步的时候。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
Sometimes if you're running and you didn't stretch, your muscles are not warm, you can
有时候如果你跑步前没拉伸，肌肉还没热身，你可能会
pull a hamstring.
拉伤腘绳肌。
All right.
好的。
So that hamstring is an important one.
所以腘绳肌很重要。
We have one more.
我们还有一个。
That's right.
没错。
We have our calves and these are in the bottom, right above our feet.
我们还有小腿，它们在腿的底部，就在脚的上方。
So I don't have any muscles except for this one because I ride my bike.
我除了这块肌肉（因为骑自行车）之外，其他肌肉都不发达。
And when you ride your bike, this gets big.
当你骑自行车时，这块肌肉会变大。
So your calves are that part of your leg above your foot, but below your knee in the back.
所以小腿就是你脚上方、膝盖后方的那部分腿。
That's right.
没错。
The back part.
后部。
Very good.
很好。
So all of these muscles, some of the most common ones that we work out.
所以所有这些肌肉，都是我们最常锻炼的一些部位。
So now let's move on to some important phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们进入流利度提升部分，学习一些重要短语。
Do you want to go catch a movie tonight?
今晚想去看场电影吗？
I can't.
我去不了。
I have to go to the gym.
我得去健身房。
Come on.
别这样嘛。
You can go tomorrow.
你可以明天去啊。
Just skip it today.
今天就跳过吧。
It's not as if you're going to get in trouble.
又不是说你会惹上什么麻烦。
Actually, I will.
其实，我会的。
I'm working out with a personal trainer that gets on my case if I don't go.
我和一个私人教练一起锻炼，如果我不去，他就会唠叨我。
I like it because it makes me feel more obligated to go and get healthy.
我喜欢这样，因为这让我更有义务去锻炼，保持健康。
That's cool.
那挺酷的。
Does your personal trainer basically teach you how to work out?
你的私人教练主要是教你如何锻炼吗？
Yeah.
是的。
He makes a workout plan depending on the areas I want to work on or the muscles I want to
他会根据我想锻炼的部位或想练的肌肉制定一个锻炼计划，
build.
比如增肌。
Like, for example, in order to get better muscle tone in my abs, pecs, and biceps, he
比如，为了让我腹肌、胸肌和二头肌线条更好，他
makes me work out with free weights.
让我用自由重量器械锻炼。
Then for my quads, calves, and hamstrings, I do leg lifts or squats.
然后对于我的股四头肌、小腿肌和腘绳肌，我会做抬腿或深蹲。
Sounds like you're really getting into shape.
听起来你身材真的变好了。
So the beginning of the dialogue, the friends were trying to decide what to do.
所以对话开头，朋友们在商量要做什么。
And one friend said, do you want to go catch a movie?
然后一个朋友说，你想去看场电影吗？
That's right.
没错。
So to catch a movie.
所以是“catch a movie”。
Do you want to go catch a movie?
你想去看场电影吗？
It sounds funny because catch means to hold something in your hands after someone throws
听起来有点好笑，因为“catch”本意是别人扔过来后用手接住，
it.
接住。
So throw and catch.
所以是“扔”和“接”。
But here, it doesn't mean to actually hold something in your hands.
但在这里，它并不是真的指用手接住什么东西。
It means do you want to go see a movie?
它的意思是“你想去看电影吗？”
Right.
对。
Exactly.
完全正确。
So it's a very informal, colloquial way of saying, hey, do you want to go to the movies?
所以这是一种非常非正式、口语化的说法，意思是“嘿，你想去看电影吗？”
Do you want to go see a movie?
你想去看电影吗？
Maybe not like a serious date or something, just for fun.
可能不是那种正式的约会之类的，只是图个乐子。
Do you want to go catch a movie?
你想去看场电影吗？
That's right.
没错。
Let's go catch a movie.
我们去看场电影吧。
All right.
好的。
So obviously we can't go to the movies because we got to go to the gym.
所以很明显我们不能去看电影，因为得去健身房。
And we have to go to the gym because our personal trainer will get on our case.
而且我们必须去健身房，因为我们的私人教练会找我们麻烦。
The personal trainer will get on my case if I don't go.
如果我不去，私人教练就会找我麻烦。
All right.
好吧。
So someone will get on my case if I don't do this.
所以如果我不做这件事，就会有人找我麻烦。
So this is an interesting way of saying, my personal trainer will criticize me or will
这是一种有趣的说法，意思是我的私人教练会批评我，或者会
be angry with me if I don't do this.
因为我不做这件事而生我的气。
That's right.
没错。
So you can use it with, for example, your parents.
所以你可以用它，比如，对你的父母。
Your parents are always getting on your case because you don't clean your room.
你的父母总是找你麻烦，因为你不打扫房间。
Yeah.
是啊。
My mom gets on my case when I don't tell her where I'm going when I go out.
我妈妈会找我麻烦，如果我不告诉她我出门去哪里。
So that means to criticize, to give you a hard time, to get angry at you or even maybe
所以这意思是批评、让你难受、生你的气，甚至可能
yell at you.
对你大喊大叫。
But you can change the pronoun.
但你可以改变代词。
So he gets on my case, but I can get on your case.
所以他找我麻烦，但我也可以找你麻烦。
That's right.
没错。
So remember that someone gets on someone else's case.
所以记住，某人找另一个人的麻烦。
That's where the person goes.
这就是那个人所在的位置。
And of course, if you want to tell that person to stop bothering you, you just say, get off
当然，如果你想告诉那个人别烦你了，你只需说，别管我。
my case.
我的事。
All right.
好吧。
So he's on her case.
所以他一直在管她的事。
Get off my case.
别管我的事。
That's right.
没错。
And now to finish things off, the whole reason why we're going to the gym is because we want
现在来收尾，我们去健身房的主要原因是我们想
to get in shape.
保持身材。
All right.
好吧。
Great phrase here to get in shape.
这里有个很好的短语“保持身材”。
This is something a lot of people like to do in the new year.
这是很多人在新年喜欢做的事。
So they say, okay, it's a new year.
所以他们会说，好吧，新的一年到了。
I want a new body.
我想要一个新的身体。
I'm going to get in shape.
我要保持身材。
That means I will lose weight, build some muscle and start to feel good.
这意味着我会减肥、增肌，并开始感觉良好。
That's right.
没错。
So we want to get in shape.
所以我们想保持身材。
Very good.
非常好。
Let's listen to our dialogue one last time.
让我们最后听一遍对话。
Do you want to go catch a movie tonight?
今晚想去看电影吗？
I can't.
我去不了。
I have to go to the gym.
我得去健身房了。
Come on.
快点。
You can go tomorrow.
你可以明天去。
Just skip it today.
今天就算了吧。
It's not as if you're going to get in trouble.
又不是说你会惹上麻烦。
Actually, I will.
实际上，我会的。
I'm working out with a personal trainer that gets on my case if I don't go.
我请了个私人教练，要是不去锻炼，他就会唠叨个不停。
I like it because it makes me feel more obligated to go and get healthy.
我喜欢它，因为它让我觉得更有义务去锻炼身体，保持健康。
That's cool.
真酷。
Does your personal trainer basically teach you how to work out?
你的私人教练基本上就是教你如何锻炼吗？
Yeah.
是的。
He makes a workout plan depending on the areas I want to work on or the muscles I want to
他根据我想锻炼的部位或肌肉来制定训练计划。
build.
build. 建造。
Like for example, in order to get better muscle tone in my abs, pecs and biceps, he makes
比如，为了让我腹肌、胸肌和肱二头肌的线条更好看，他让我
me work out with free weights.
我用自由重量训练。
Then for my quads, calves and hamstrings, I do leg lifts or squats.
然后针对我的股四头肌、小腿和腘绳肌，我会做抬腿或深蹲。
Seems like you're really getting into shape.
看起来你身材越来越好了。
Going to the gym, getting a personal trainer, what do you think?
去健身房，请个私人教练，你觉得怎么样？
Is it a good idea or a bad idea?
这是个好主意还是坏主意？
I think for some people who have a hard time getting motivated, so people who don't like
我想对于某些很难找到动力的人来说，也就是那些不喜欢……的人。
to go to the gym, it's a great idea because having another person push you can really
去健身房是个好主意，因为有人推你一把真的能
help.
帮上忙。
I think for other people who are already pushing themselves, it's not as helpful.
我觉得对于那些已经在自我激励的人来说，这没那么有用。
I think also if you just start out going to the gym, I think you should get a personal
我也觉得如果你刚开始去健身房，头几周应该请个私人
trainer for the first couple of weeks because you really have to understand and learn what
教练，因为你必须真正理解和学习
you're doing and the purpose of that exercise and figure out how many sets, how many repetitions.
你在做什么、这个练习的目的，还要弄清楚做多少组、多少次重复。
This is very important because some people just go and they overwork it.
这非常重要，因为有些人去了就过度锻炼。
They do and they don't know how to use the machines or the weights.
他们确实如此，而且不知道怎么用器械或举重。
You can actually harm yourself.
你实际上可能会伤到自己。
You can pull a hamstring or something if you don't know what you're doing.
如果你不知道自己在做什么，可能会拉伤腿筋之类的。
For people who've never learned how to exercise, maybe it's a good idea like you say.
对于从未学过如何锻炼的人来说，也许像你说的那样是个好主意。
It's a very interesting thing.
这挺有意思的。
Actually gyms as well, very popular nowadays, especially with the holidays passing.
实际上健身房现在也很流行，尤其是假期过后。
People gain some holiday weight.
人们会胖一些。
You got to go back to the gym to lose that weight.
你得回健身房减掉那些体重。
That's right.
没错。
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Do you go to the gym?
你去健身房吗？
If so, what parts of your body do you like to focus on?
如果去的话，你喜欢重点锻炼身体的哪些部位？
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好吧。
We'll see you guys there.
我们到时候见。
Take care.
保重。
Bye bye.
再见。